Hello friends, welcome to Market Gyan
channel. ICICI Lord has published its third
quarter results. Let us
see how the company performed
in the third quarter. If we talk about the total income of the company, then
in the present quarter the total income of the company is Rs.
5883 crores, whereas in the last quarter the
total income of the company was Rs.
5800.50 crores. So, there are not many significant changes in the
company's income on quarter-on-quarter basis.
If we look at the last year, the company's income
was Rs. 50004 crores. So, there are
not many significant changes on quarter-on-quarter basis,
but on year-on-year basis, an increase of about 16 to 17 percent is being
seen in the company's
income.
If we talk about the expenditure of the company, then
in the present quarter the expenditure of the company
is Rs. 5197 crores, whereas
in the last quarter the expenditure of the company was Rs.
5186 crores. So, there are
some significant changes in the expenditure of the company on quarter-on-quarter basis.
No, but if seen last year, the
company's expenditure was Rs
4588 crore, so here on year-on-year basis, the
company's expenditure is also
seen increasing. If we talk about the company's profit (
PAT), then
in the current quarter the company's profit
after tax is Rs 724 crore, which
in the last quarter the company's PAT was Rs 693 crore.
Here, on a quarter-on-quarter basis, an increase of 4 to
5 percent is being seen.
If seen last year in the company's PAT, then the
company's profit after tax was Rs 431
crore, so here on a quarter-on-quarter
basis, it is around 3 to 4 percent, but on a year-on-year
basis, a huge jump has been seen,
which is an increase of around 70 to 75 percent on a
year-on-year basis. If we
talk about the company's EPS (earnings per
share), then in the present quarter the company
's EPS is 14.6, whereas in the last quarter the
company's EPS was 14.05, if we
look at the last year  In the December quarter of 2023, the
company's EPS was 88.7, so here the
company's EPS is also seeing an increase on both quarter-on-
quarter and year-on-year basis.
If we talk about the
shareholding pattern in the company,
then the shareholding of the promoters has been seen to be
declining marginally from the previous quarter.
In the last quarter, the shareholding of the promoters
was 51.8, which has
decreased to 51.6 in this quarter.
If we look at the shareholding of FIIs, then
marginal changes have been seen, which has
increased. A marginal increase has been seen.
In the last quarter, the shareholding of DIs
was 23.95, whereas in this quarter, the
shareholding of FIIs is 24.75.
If we look at the shareholding of DIs, then
in the last quarter, the shareholding of DIs
was 17.15, which has decreased to
16.5. There are not many significant changes in this quarter. There has been a
very marginal increase in the shareholding pattern of FIIs.
Marginal declines have been seen in DII share holding.
Thanks, see you
in the next video.